simmarket.com 2019-02-26

# simMarket: Flight, Train, Ship and Simulation Games, Aviation Videos, Books

Unless stated otherwise below, the provision of your personal data is neither legally nor contractually obligatory, nor required for conclusion of a contract. You are not obliged to provide your data. Not providing it will have no consequences. This only applies as long as the processing procedures below do not state otherwise.  
“Personal data” is any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.

**Responsible for data processing**  
The person responsible for data processing on this website in terms of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is:  
simFlight GmbH  
Werner-von-Siemens-Str. 28  
24568 Kaltenkirchen  
Germany

Email: ​[privacy@simflight.com](mailto:privacy@simflight.com)

The person responsible for the processing of personal data is the natural or legal person who alone or together with others decides on the purposes and means of processing personal data.

**Server log files**  
You can use our websites without submitting personal data. Every time you access our website, user data is transmitted by your internet browser and stored in protocol files (server log files). This stored data includes e.g. name of the site called up, date and time of the request, amount of data transferred and the provider making the request. This data serves exclusively to ensure smooth operation of our website and to improve our offering. It is not possible to assign this data to a particular person.

**Collection and processing when using the contact form / Ticket from / Comment form**  
When you use the contact form, the ticket form and the Comment form we will only collect your personal data (name, email address, message text) in the scope provided by you. The data processing is for the purpose of making contact. By submitting your message you agree to the processing of your transmitted data. Processing will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR with your consent.You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us without affecting the legality of the processing carried out with your consent up to the withdrawal. We will only use your email address to process your request. Finally your data will be deleted, unless you have agreed to further processing and use.

**Customer account**  
When you open a customer account, we will collect your personal data in the scope given there. The data processing is for the purpose of improving your shopping experience and simplifying order processing. The processing will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR with your consent. You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us without affecting the legality of the processing carried out with your consent up to the withdrawal. Your customer account will then be deleted.

**Collection, processing, and use of personal data in orders**  
When you submit an order, we only collect and use your personal data where this is necessary for the fulfilment and handling of your requests. The provision of data is necessary for conclusion of a contract. Failure to provide it will prevent the conclusion of any contract. The processing will occur on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR and is required for the fulfilment of a contract with you. We will notforward your data to third parties without your explicit consent. This only excludes our service partners which we require in order to handle the contractual relationship or service providers we use to process an order. Along with the recipients named in the clauses of this data protection declaration, these may be recipients in the following categories: Shipping providers, payment service providers, merchandise management service providers, service providers for order processing, web hosts, IT service providers and dropshipping dealers. We will comply strictly with legal requirements in every case. The scope of data transmission is restricted to a minimum.

**Use of your email address for mailing of newsletters**  
We use your email address outside of contractual processing exclusively to send you a newsletter for our own marketing purposes, if you have explicitly agreed to this. The processing will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR with your consent. You can withdraw your consent at any time without affecting the legality of the processing carried out with your consent up to the withdrawal. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time using the relevant link in the newsletter or by contacting us. Your email address will then be removed from the distributor. Your data will be forwarded to a service provider for email marketing in the course of order processing. It will not be forwarded to other third parties.

**Using PayPal**  
When paying via PayPal we transmit your payment data to PayPal (Europe) S.a.r.l. et Cie, S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg (hereinafter “PayPal”). The transfer takes place in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point b GDPR and only insofar as this is necessary for payment processing. For further information on data protection law, including the credit agencies used, please refer to PayPal’s data protection declaration at: [https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-ful​l](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

**Using Alipay**  
If you choose one of the payment methods offered by Wirecard, payment is processed via the payment service provider ​Wirecard Bank AG | Einsteinring 35 | 85609 Aschheim, Deutschland,​ to which we pass on your information provided during the order process together with the information about your order (name, address, possibly IBAN, possibly BIC, invoice amount, currency and possibly transaction number). Your data will only be passed on to the payment service provider checkoutportal by wirecard for the purpose of payment processing in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 letter b GDPR. Your data will only be passed on if this is actually necessary for processing the payment. Wirecard’s Data Privacy Statement can be found here: ​<https://www.wirecard.com/privacy-protection/>

**Using Credit Cards, IDEAL** If you choose one of the payment methods offered by Stripe, payment is processed by Stripe Payments Europe Ltd, Block 4, Harcourt Centre, Harcourt Road, Dublin 2, Ireland,,​ to which we pass on your information provided during the order process together with the information about your order (name, address, possibly IBAN, possibly BIC, invoice amount, currency and possibly transaction number). Your data will only be passed on to the payment service provider checkoutportal by wirecard for the purpose of payment processing in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 letter b GDPR. Your data will only be passed on if this is actually necessary for processing the payment.Stripe’s Data Privacy Statement can be found here: ​<https://stripe.com/de/privacy>

**Using Sofort (direct bank transfer)**  
If you choose one of the payment methods offered by SOFORT, payment is processed by SOFORT GmbH, Theresienhöhe 12, 80339 München, Deutschland, to which we pass on your information provided during the order process together with the information about your order (name, address, possibly IBAN, possibly BIC, invoice amount, currency and possibly transaction number). Your data will only be passed on to the payment service provider checkoutportal by wirecard for the purpose ofpayment processing in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 letter b GDPR. Your data will only be passed on if this is actually necessary for processing the payment.Stripe’s Data Privacy Statement can be found here: [h​ttps://www.klarna.com/sofort/datenschutz](https://secure.simmarket.com/h%E2%80%8Bttps://www.klarna.com/sofort/datenschutz/)

**Cookies** Our website uses cookies. Cookies are small text files which are saved in a user’s internet browser or by the user’s internet browser on their computer system. When a user calls up a website, a cookie may be saved on the user’s operating system. This cookie contains a characteristic character string which allows the browser to be clearly identified when the website is called up again. We use cookies to make our offering more user-friendly, effective and secure. Cookies also allow our systems to recognise your browser after a page change and to offer you services. Some functions of our website cannot be offered without the use of cookies. These services require the browser to be recognised again after a page change.  
Our website also uses cookies to allow us to analyse the surfing behaviour of visitors to our website.

We also use cookies to address visitors to other websites with targeted marketing relating to their interests.

Processing is carried out on the basis of § 15 (3) TMG (Telemedia Act) as well as art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR due to our justified interest in the purposes above. The data collected in this way is pseudonymised using technological measures. It is therefore not possible to connect the data to your person. The data will not be stored together with other personal data pertaining to you. **_You have the right to veto this processing of your personal data according to art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR by contacting us, for reasons relating to your personal situation.​_** Cookies will be stored on your computer. You therefore have full control over the use of cookies. By choosing corresponding technical settings in your internet browser, you can prevent the storage of cookies and transmission of the data they contain. Cookies which have already been saved may be deleted at any time. We would, however, like to point out that this may prevent you from making full use of all the functions of this website. Using the links below, you can find out how to manage cookies (or deactivate them, among other things) in major browsers:

Chrome Browser: <https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en>  
Internet Explorer:​ <https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>  
Mozilla Firefox: <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences>  
Safari: <https://support.apple.com/guide/safari/manage-cookies-and-website-data-sfri11471/mac>

**Use of YouTube**  
Our website uses YouTube LLC’s function for the embedding of YouTube videos. (901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA; “YouTube”). YouTube is an affiliated company of Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA;“Google”). This feature shows YouTube videos in an iFrame on the website. The option “advanced privacy mode” is enabled here. This prevents YouTube from storing information on visitors to the website. It is only if you watch a video that information is transmitted to and stored by YouTube.Further information on the data collected and used by YouTube and Google, your rights and privacy can be found in YouTube’s privacy policy ([​https://www.youtube.com/t/privacy​](https://www.youtube.com/t/privacy%E2%80%8B)).

**Use of social media buttons.**  
In order to increase the protection of your data when you visit our website, these buttons are not fully integrated into the page as plug-ins and only fully operational when using an HTML link. This type of integration ensures that no connection to the respective social media servers is established when a page of our website containing such buttons is accessed. When you click on the button, a new browser window opens and calls up the respective social media page, where you can interact with the plug-ins there (if necessary after entering your login data).

**Duration of storage**  
After contractual processing has been completed, the data is initially stored for the duration of the warranty period, then in accordance with the retention periods prescribed by law, especially tax and commercial law, and then deleted after the period has elapsed, unless you have agreed to further processing and use.

**Rights of the affected person**  
If the legal requirements are fulfilled, you have the following rights according to art. 15 to 20 GDPR: Right to information, correction, deletion, restriction of processing, data portability. You also have a right of objection against processing based on art. 6 (1) GDPR, and to processing for the purposes of direct marketing, according to art. 21 (1) GDPR.

Contact us at any time. Our contact details can be found in our imprint.

**Right to complain to the regulatory authority**  
You have the right to complain to the regulatory authority according to art. 77 GDPR if you believe that your data is not being processed legally.
